大富豪　バッテラだ。
In the palace, the King has
completed his recovery, and continues to play Gungi without rest.
目的？　もちろん 『グリードアイランド』ですよ。
That's checkmate.
ですから　愛ですよ　愛。
Her mind and body are at their limit.
愛するものを独占したいと 思うのは　当然でしょう。 愛とは？
I estimate it will only take another
match or two before the King wins.
今　何時だ？ あ…　クラピカ！
If you can barely sit straight,
the victory won't satisfy me. Recover your strength.
半日も…　寝ていたのか。
Even while his arm was being treated,
the King never stopped playing.
丸２日だぜ　クラピカ ボスは？　地下競売は？
But now he changes his mind?
結局　中止になったわ。
This female is dangerous.
残りの品は　後日 ネットオークションになるそうよ。 ボスも納得してくれたわ。
If this continues, she could prove quite troublesome...
スクワラが殺されたの。 えっ？ それで　エリザが ひどく取り乱しちゃって。
Then, I will excuse myself.
ボスは　そのことより
I must not be too hasty.
エリザの動揺ぶりに ショックを受けていたわ。
The King chose to retract his decree. In order to stay true to his convictions...
それで　自分から 「帰る」って言い出して…。
In order to defeat the Gungi
Champion at her best...
そうか。
In order to demonstrate his strength!
ゴンとキルアは？ ２人は元気よ　今頃は…。 寝ちまったよ。 あっ…。
If I kill this girl now, the King will remain a loser at Gungi forever.
あいつらは 自分のやるべきことをやってる。
as someone the King could never defeat!
幻のゲーム 『グリードアイランド』です！
I am such a fool!
お！
My hasty impulse could have left
the King with a permanent scar!
お！ ご覧の通り　その不思議な力は
Once I have seen the King conquer the world...
この中で　誰かが プレーし続けている限り！
Using Knov-san's Apartment Complex,
seven people will infiltrate the palace.
現在もプレーヤーとして ゲーム内に存在しております。 実は　このゲームは 彼との契約によって
Shoot and me... Gon, Killua, Meleoron, Ikalgo, and then Morel.
当オークションに 譲渡されたものなのです。 ジンが持って来たんじゃ ないんだ…
A few seconds after us, the Chairman will enter from beyond Pitou's En.
ジェイトサリは　次のような 契約書を残しておりました。
During that time, we must draw
the Royal Guard from the King.
「本契約書に記載された 年月日までに
Gon, Killua, and Ikalgo will go in first.
このゲームが クリアされなかった場合 その時点で　私を含めた７名が プレー中であったとしても
When we suddenly appear
in the midst of the palace, their immediate reaction will be...
無償で　このゲーム７本を ハード機とともに
To protect the King with their lives.
サザンピースオークションに 提供し
They'll probably use a formation like this.
才能ある後輩に　ゲームクリアの 夢を託すことにする」と。 残念ながら　我々が入手した時
Breaking it won't be easy. And that's where I come in.
それでは　９億ジェニーから お願いします！
Okay, any questions?
１０億　出ました！ １５億　出ました！ １０５番　倍！　３０億！
Uh, about Palm... Can we do anything to learn
what's happened to her?
７１番　さらに倍！　６０億！
She's either dead or in hiding. If she'd gotten out, she'd have contacted us.
挙げた手の形で 金額を表すんだね。 ああ　オークショニアが その中から
Since she hasn't, that's the only explanation. If she were captured,
she'd have taken her own life.
瞬時に　一番高い額を 発表するんだ。
When she left, she was prepared for that.
じゃあ　これは？
If we try to check in on her,
it would be an insult to her resolve.
２０１番　さらに倍！ ２４０億！
Hey, you're being too harsh!
バカ！　お前！ チッ。
Gon's just concerned about Palm. And his concern is worthless.
はぁ　助かった。
You just came back! Where do you get off?!
どうやら　兄貴の野郎 『グリードアイランド』のロムを 解析できなかったらしいな ７１番　２５５億！
Assuming that Palm was captured alive, it would mean the enemy knows our plan.
あいつ！　いくら持ってんだよ フン。
Which would make us like moths
flying straight into the flame.
１６番 一気にアップで　３０５億です！
We'll be destroyed instantly.
クッソ！
But instead of worrying about worst-case scenarios, what's important is that we trust Palm.
フ。 ３０５億…　ですか。 別に構わん。 このゲームをクリアすることが できるのならばな。
Well, that certainly makes sense, but Gon's point might be that, if Palm has met such a fate, we still
have time to change the plan. Think again.
あの　俺達 ハンターなんですけど…。
He'll say that we have to save Palm first.
『グリードアイランド』の ゲームクリアに協力しますよ。
But he won't offer any plans for that.
ふざけてないで さっさと帰りなさい。
Right? R-Right...
ふざけてないよ！ これでもプロハンターなんだ！ 何をバカな。
I see your point...
ライセンスはあるのかね？ はい！ いや　ないよ　まだ質屋だろ。
I know you're worried, but once the operation starts,
you'll have to forget her until we're done.
あっ　いや　今は…。 ほら見ろ　やっぱりウソか。 ウソじゃ　ないよ！
If you're distracted for a fraction of a second, that might cause our operation to fail.
まぁ　待ちなさい　この会場に 入れたというだけでも
We still have two days...
君達が特別なのは分かる。
There's still time for Palm to contact us.
ゲームクリアを 目指しているのは事実だが
Nyow I understand.
プレー人数が 限られているからねぇ。
Should I have tried to escape to the right?
マズい　作戦失敗か…
You should have moved your knight.
((ぶっちゃけ　ゲームは 買わなくてもいいと思うんだ)) ((欲しいのは ゲームの中の情報！))
I didn't want to let a single piece
control the center of the board.
((それに　『グリードアイランド』を 競り落とした人の中にも
Sometimes, you must accept
the risk and move forward.
きっと　プレーヤーを 探している人もいると思うんだ))
Otherwise, you won't ever be
able to make me hesitate.
プレー人数が限られてる？ １つのカードには　１人分のデータしか セーブできないんだよ。
I am unaccustomed to playing a waiting game.
マルチタップを使い　１つのハードで ８人がプレーヤーの上限だ。
Your Majesty... What is it? I have some sensitive information,
so we should step outside.
そういえば　メモリーカードの ３０ブロック全部
It's fine, speak.
『グリードアイランド』で 埋まってたよね？ ああ。 なぜ　それを！
Two days remain until the National Celebration.
俺達　『グリードアイランド』の セーブデータを持ってるんです。 君達　プレーしたことがあるのか？
The number of citizens to process in Peijing
has increased beyond our expectations.
いえ　データだけ 手に入れたんですけど。 だとしたら　あれも…
But the weather forecast is favorable,
so the selection should proceed as planned. Get to the point.
ゲーム機から そのカードを抜くために
I would like to move up
もう１つ　アイテムが 必要なんだが。
the post-selection schedule.
もしかして！
That's it? Do as you wish.
あの指輪か！ 指輪のことも知っている
Yes, sir. In that case, we will depart
immediately after the selection— Don't make me repeat myself!
どうやら　審査対象としての 資格はあるようだねぇ。
I'm telling you to decide on your own.
「念」は　使えるんだろう？
Do not return until I summon you.
フッ！ フッ！
Well, we only need to wait for the King to win.
どうだ？
You think that will only be a
few more matches, right? No.
ダメですね プレーさせるだけ無駄です。
Wasn't that what you said a while ago?
逃げ回った揚げ句 死ぬのがオチですな。
The King is improving at a remarkable rate.
やってもみないで　何で分かるの？
However, she is also evolving.
やってからじゃ遅いんだよ　坊や。 死んでくれるのなら　まだいいが
I am no longer able to predict the outcome.
ダラダラと延命されるのが 厄介でな。
Well, it's still only a matter of
time before the King wins.
あのゲームは　プレーヤーが 中で生きている限り
I hope you're right.
リセットも　メモリーカードを 抜くこともできない。
I am. There's nothing to worry about.
私が雇ったハンターが プロ　アマ含めて １００名ほどプレーしているが
I am one hundred percent confident
that he's acting on his own...
その半分以上が すでに投げている。 「投げてる」？
The man who defeated Leol.
現実世界に戻ることを諦め
The reports from Welfin and Brovada confirm it.
ずっと　ゲームの中で 生き延びようとしているのだ。
The soldiers under his control
are all smoke puppets.
だから 新たなプレーヤーは厳選する。 我々が求めているのは
Since their complex movements
are not typical of Nen puppets, they fooled me as effectively as a smokescreen.
最低でも 現実に戻れるアイテムを入手し 帰還できるだけの 力を持つ者だ。 俺達には　その力がないってこと？
He can't control as many puppets as I can,
but his are more responsive.
何で　こいつに そんなこと　分かるんだよ！
I want to fight him...
それは　彼がプロのハンターで
But I can't leave my post.
『グリードアイランド』の 経験者だからだ。 えっ!? えっ!?
Maybe he'll come to me...
現実帰還のアイテム入手難度は 中の下。 だが　お前達程度の「念」では 入手どころか
It's about time for us to enter Peijing.
すぐに　ゲームオーバーだ。
The enemy should have noticed
Morel's distraction by now.
審査が終われば 俺は　またゲームに戻る。
We'll make some noise in Peijing to negate
審査？ あんたが　プレーヤーを 審査するってこと？
their belief that this is all the work of one man.
そうだ 審査日はオークション最終日。
At the same time, many citizens will be moving toward the palace.
もし　参加する気があるのなら その間　せいぜい 「念」を磨くことだな。 言われなくったってやるよ！ 行こう！　キルア。
If we disappear the day before the celebration, they'll believe assassins are hidden
among the citizens, trying to kill the King.
ところで坊や そのメモリーカードは どうやって入手したんだ？
And their focus will be outside
the palace, on the crowds.
教えない！ ハハハ…。
That's when we enter the palace with
Four-Dimensional Apartment Complex!
クッソ！　腹立つなぁ。
The King will definitely be here.
絶対　審査　受かってやる！ 審査か…　どうする？
Watching the selection from
the third-floor throne room.
聞くまでもないね。
Will he really be there?
カードが１つ ささってるってことは あと１人しか　プレーできねえぜ？
2-1-3, pawn. 4-5-1, knight.
マルチタップ　使うね。 これで４人　ＯＫね。
8-7-2, lieutenant general.
なる で　どっちが先に行く？ 私　行くよ。
4-3-3, archer.
お！　ホントに消えちまった。
As we play, she's getting sharper.
半信半疑だったんだがな。
2-1-1, knight.
何？　今の。 ゲームだよ お前らもやらないか？
6-6-1, major general.
パス。 気が向いたらな。
But it does not pain me.
そうか…　じゃ　お先に。
Rather, I find this enjoyable. Because the board dictates my every move.
また消えた。 どんなゲームなの？　これ。 実際に死ぬかもしれねえ ゲームだってよ。
Which proves that she is still
several levels above me.
オークションの カタログに書いてある。
How strong can she become?
ふん。
Supreme Leader...
あ　ムカつく！
I feel...
言いたい放題 言ってくれちゃって！
strange.
そう突っかかるなよ。
I can't stop.
そろそろ次の段階を考えても いい頃だってこと。 次の段階？ 「発」…　つまり必殺技さ。
Marvelous moves keep flooding into my mind...
えっ？
I can become even better!
クラピカが　「念」を習得したのは 俺達と　ほとんど同じ時期。
Has she awakened?
にもかかわらず あいつが　「旅団」と
Then she's only
対等に戦えるのは 必殺技のおかげ。
begun to grow.
うん　クラピカは「旅団」に対して 無敵に近い能力を得る代わりに 命懸けのリスクを 背負ったんだよね。
That's checkmate.
俺達は　そうはいかない。 うん。
Could I take a short break?
リスクは重過ぎず　軽過ぎず かつ　自分の系統に合ってて
It's the first time she's asked for a break...
実践的であり　応用の利く そんな能力を考えるんだ。 うん。
Is something wrong? No, I'd like to return to my room to
record the moves that are in my mind. But you can't see...
まぁ　そうなるわな。
Oh, I'll just move the pieces around the board!
１つずつ行こうぜ まず　どんな能力にしたいかだな。 「どんな能力に」か…。
When I touch the pieces after they're placed, I will never forget their position.
おい　何かあるだろ？ 漠然とでもさ。
She's memorized every placement
she's ever experienced? Very well, you're excused.
うん　とにかく　すごい能力！
Thank you.
漠然とし過ぎ！
A foolish question...
じゃあ　まずは自分の系統から 考えてみようぜ。 ゴンは強化系なんだから
Her name...
やっぱ　何かを強める能力が いいわけだよ。 うん。
Hey. What is your name?
だとすると　次は　お前の何を どう強めるかってことだな。
You mean mine? Is there anyone else around?
痛ったいな！ じゃあキルアは　どうなのさ！
It's K-K-Komugi.
とっくにあるよ。
Komugi?
だから　お前のほうを 決めようとしてんだろ？
Supreme Leader...
ホント？　どんなの？
Can you please tell me
秘密。 え！ ゴン　俺は今日から 必殺技の特訓に入る。
what your name is?
まっ　お前は　ゆっくり考えてろ。
My name?
もしかしたら　審査には 俺だけ合格しちゃうかもな！
What...
あいつ すぐ横道にそれるからな
Pitou.
自分のオーラと電気を 融合するイメージ
Yes, what do you need? Pouf. Yes. Youpi.
うっ　うぅ！
Is something the matter? Pouf...
次は　ためた電力を 一気に放電するイメージで
Right, you're Pouf.
「念」を練る！
Then... What is my name?
フッ。
I speak with utmost respect, Your Majesty...
((お前達程度の「念」では すぐに　ゲームオーバーだ))
You are the King. You have no other name.
クッソ！　絶対　見返してやる！
You are the one and only King.
熱心だな　ゴン。 クラピカ！　もういいの？ ああ　熱は　下がった もう大丈夫だ。
At the moment, there are impostors
using that name without permission, but we will eliminate them all.
全然　大丈夫じゃなさそう でも　クラピカのことだから
So that the entire world will
know there is only one King.
「クモ」が　まだヨークシンにいることが 分かったら…
That assumes the others can be eliminated. "King" is a title.
何とか止める方法　ないかな？
A title can be bestowed, and it is not a name.
ところで オークションは　どうだった？
What of you, Youpi?
高価なゲームを 狙ってるそうじゃないか。
Your question is far beyond my capacity.
あっ　うん。
I cannot think of a way to provide an answer.
なるほど プレーヤー選考審査か。 ねぇ　クラピカは 一体どんな修行をしたの？
Pitou. I believe that your feelings
are what matter most.
鎖を具現化しようと思ってからは イメージ修行だな。
You should select the name
that you find most pleasing.
目をつぶって　感触を確認したり 何百　何千枚と写生したり
Very well, then.
ただ眺めてみたり　舐めてみたり 音や　においも…。 鎖で遊ぶ以外　何もするなと 師匠に言われたからな。
You can choose a name after the selection. Right now, our priority is to finish all the
preparations before tomorrow morning.
しばらくして 鎖を取り上げられた。
Your Majesty, is something wrong?
そうすると　今度は 幻覚で鎖が見えて来るんだ。
If you have any concerns, we shall address them.
その幻覚の鎖に やがて　重たさや冷たさ
That is why we are here.
こすれ合う音を感じるようになる。
Komugi's entire body was glowing.
そうして自然と　具現化した鎖が 出せるようになったんだ。
Komugi? The girl with the closed eyes.
それ以外は　ゴン達と同じだよ 「纏」と「練」だ。
He's remembered that human's name.
うん。
She experienced an awakening.
あっ　そうだ　クラピカ！ 俺の師匠になってよ！ クラピカなら　的確に悪いとことか 指摘してくれそうだもん！
Komugi will now become much stronger,
although only at Gungi.
これなら　オークションの間
Pitou... Yes.
クラピカを ここに足止めできる！
If Komugi were put through the selection
残念だが　それはできない。 えっ!?
that will occur tomorrow, what would happen?
私のボスが 明日にでも　ここをたつ。
She would die. The selection chooses humans
立場上　ついて行かねばならない。 ヨークシンを出るの？ ああ。
with the physical and mental
strength to serve as soldiers.
「クモ」のことは 確かに　心残りだが
The survivors will be those who demonstrate
excellent combat capabilities.
あれから　すでに２日経った今では もう奴らも　ここには　いまい。
Your Majesty, please...
そっか　それがいいよ。 ゴンは　誰に「念」を教わったんだ？
After meeting Komugi, I've learned that strength can
manifest in different ways.
私に聞くより　その人に 聞いたほうがいいんじゃないか？
For example, during our trip here... Your Majesty, please stop.
ハハハ…　必殺技か 君達らしいね。
...I killed a child. Your Majesty, you must not say it...
結論から言うと　強化系に 必殺技は必要ありません。
Perhaps that child...
[TEL]　何でですか？
It isn't right... It's inappropriate!
６つの系統の中で　最も 攻守のバランスがいいからです。
...had the potential to surpass
me in a certain field.
「纏」と「練」を極めて行けば
An almighty King... Yet I extinguished that potential.
それが必殺技と呼べるほど すごい威力となる。
...can never show regret!
でも　今は　時間がないんです。
I extinguished it for no real reason.
どうしても俺　４日後の審査に…。 [TEL]　ゴンくん もし　私が審査員で
You must not say any more! I am...
付け焼き刃の必殺技もどきなど 見せられたら　失望するでしょう。
King!
はい。 マネではなく　今のゴンくんでも
I took a life for no reason at all...
十分　特別な力を 発揮できると思いますよ。 本当!? [TEL]　もちろん！
What tremendous strength I must possess!
[TEL]　自分に何ができるかを 一つ一つ思い出してみなさい。 [TEL]　そうすれば おのずと答えは出て来ます。
I appear with no warning, to rob
countless beings of their inferior strength! To crush... To destroy.
[TEL] あっ…。
That is my power.
[TEL]　ヒント　お願い ヒントをください！ 随分　焦ってるみたいですねぇ。
Brute force is the strongest
power in this world!
期限がなければ 俺も　そう思うんだけど…。 しょうがない　大ヒント！
I am not worthy of being a Royal Guard... Why not?
ゴンくんが　そのツェズゲラ という人の前で見せたのは 普通の「練」だけでしょう？ [TEL]　うん。
I jumped to the wrong conclusion, and I nearly insulted the King.
今度は　全てを同時に見せなさい。 全てを？ [TEL]　そうです。 [TEL]　いいですか？ 君が覚えたこと全部
I was foolish enough to think that the King
might have regretted his actions...
それを同時にです。
You always think too much.
覚えたこと　全てを同時に
Well, the King has changed since that girl arrived. Yes, that is true.
「纏」　オーラを 肉体の周りにとどめる
If the girl will impede the King,
we should kill her.
「絶」　オーラが 全く出ていない状態にする
To think my mind operates
on the same level as yours...
「練」　通常以上の 大量のオーラを生み出す そして　「発」
Yes... My power is the strongest that exists.
待てよ 「練」は　オーラを出すことで 「絶」は　出さない
All other power means nothing
in the face of my own.
それを同時にって…
They are as dust in the wind.
しっかりしろよ　ゴン もたもたしてっと 一気に置いてくぜ！
Her skill is in Gungi, a simple board game.
無理だよ　出るのと出ないの 同時にやるなんて
I could turn her into no more than
a source of meat with the barest touch. So her life depends on my mood.
((自分に何ができるかを 一つ一つ思い出してみなさい))
If I change my mind, I can immediately kill her!
うん　ウイングさんに 念能力を開発してもらって
Then why am I so hesitant?
最初は「纏」しか覚えてないのに
The goal was to kill time while
waiting for the selection.
バトルに出ちゃって 大ケガしたんだ
The selection is tomorrow...
Haven't I had enough?
でも そこで「絶」をマスターした
I've had my fun. I no longer need her.
それから　ヒソカの技を 見破るために「凝」を覚えて…
Do I kill her now?!
集中？　そうだ 気持も目に集中してたから
Th-Thank you very much...
他の部分が　どうなってるか 気づかなかった
Why did you not call for help?
わずかだけど オーラが出てる
Here... And here... You're covered in blood!
これを閉じれば 全て同時にできる！
Damn, I don't believe it.
よしっ　できた！
I don't want to bother anyone else.
あっ！ ぷは　ダメだ。
You aren't bothering anyone.
ちょっと気を抜いただけで 全部　解けちゃう
What am... You are an important guest!
でも　できる
...I saying?
これで　もし「練」で増強した オーラを１か所に集中したら
Didn't I come here to kill her?
)
Why do you cry?!
オス！
Why can't I do it? I'm sorry!
何か　つかんだな
But... But...
負けないぜ！　ゴン！
No one's ever been this nice to me!
２人は　今 新たな覚醒の時を迎えていた
What is this creature?